While I waited for the results of JAXA's final astronaut selection exam,
なんば　むった
ジャクサ
(南波六太)＜ＪＡＸＡ 宇宙飛行士
選抜試験➡
その合格発表を待つ中
ひびと
弟 日々人はついに月面へ…＞
my brother, Hibito, finally landed on the moon.
(南波日々人)おおっ！
イエーッ‼
Yay!!
よし！データ送信 完了！
Okay, finished transmitting the data.
終わったぁ～！でっ！
All done!
(バディ)どうした ヒビト？
What's wrong, Hibito?
ってえ～！
Ow...
＜そして私の方はと言うと…＞
What have I been doing?
These last few days,
＜この２～３日 プチ幸運が
異常に続いていた＞
I've been catching all these little lucky breaks.
＜引き出しの奥から
商品券が現れたり…＞
I opened my drawer and found a gift certificate.
Gift Certificate
Accepted at all stores nationwide.
My total was precisely 777 yen,
＜合計額が
７７７円になったり…➡
しかも小銭がピッタリだったり＞
and I had exact change.
＜茶柱が 必要以上に立ったり…➡
And there were multiple tea stalks floating upright in my cup.
逆に怖い！逆に不吉！＞
It's actually a bit scary!
And ominous, as well!
＜やけについてる日々に
私の不安は募るばかり＞
Things are going so well, I'm getting really worried.
＜私が合格するかどうかは➡
Whether I pass or not is going to come down to luck.
もう 運に頼るしか
ないってのに…➡
Luck
限られている運は どんどん減って
多分もう すっからかんに近い！＞
What little I had is being drained.
I'm probably running on empty!
[TV](女)｢タカノリさん…私
幸せすぎて何だか怖いわ｣
Takanori...
I'm so happy, it scares me.
What are you saying?
[TV](男)｢何を言ってるんだい｣
And finally,
＜そしてとうとう…＞
＜特に不運も起こらぬまま
合格発表の朝を迎えてしまった＞
with nothing unlucky happening,
it's the morning of Judgment Day.
[TV](女)｢キャー！タカノリさん！｣
Takanori!
Seven Days
Space Brothers
Before my uneasiness
was the end
of my happiness
I came to you
and we were one
Hello Hello
Let's fly
Here in this world we dream
and keep on dancing
Here among light and shadow
we keep changing
so that the wind doesn't let up
Even though the future is vague and unreliable
we are
not alone
#37 Two Men in the Park
[TV](女性ｷｬｽﾀｰ)
さあ今日の占い １位から
最下位までの発表で～す｡
Time for today's horoscopes.
Here's the ranking, from first to last.
[TV]まずは７位から１１位｡
First, are 7th through 11th place.
Those with December birthdays are in trouble...
[TV]１２月生まれのみなさん｡
[TV]今日はいまひとつ
さえていませんね～｡
But cheer up, and stick it out!
[TV]元気を出して ガンバロー！
Next, we have 2nd through 6th place.
[TV]そして２位から６位は ご覧の
通り｡７月生まれのみなさん｡
Here you are!
July birthdays have great luck today.
[TV]今日はとっても
ラッキーですよ！
《むむ…ここにも入ってない》
Something good will happen.
They haven't called my month yet.
And now, we have number one!
[TV]それでは今日の１位は！
Born October 28
《１０月 １０月…》
October, October...
[TV]９月生まれのみなさ～ん！
恋愛運が最高ですよ～｡
All you September births, today's the perfect day for romance.
[TV]そして ごめんなさ～い｡
今日の最下位は…｡
And sorry...
Today is the worst day for those born in October.
[TV]１０月生まれの あなた！
《マジかよ…》
Seriously?
The lucky item for those born in October
[TV]１０月生まれのあなたの
ラッキーアイテムは!?
is a little pink bicycle.
[TV]ピンクの小さい自転車です！
I don't have one of those...
《そんなの持ってねぇ…》
(鶴見)よう｡
Hey.
(星加)全部１人で
電話する気か？ツルミー｡
You planning to call everyone yourself, Tsurumi?
(鶴見)分けてほしいのか？
Want to share the load?
(星加)俺だって｢あなたは
合格です｣とか言いたいよ｡
I'd like to tell people they've passed.
じゃあ 半分分けてやろう｡
ただし…➡
Then you can take half the candidates.
But...
不合格を伝える辛さも
味わってもらうぞ｡
You'll also have to deal with telling people they failed.
当然だ｡
Naturally.
合格が２人と不合格が２人か…｡
Two passing candidates and two failing candidates...
じゃ 行ってくる｡
Then I'm off.
は？どこへ？
Where are you going?
外だよ｡俺は こういうのは…➡
Outside.
I believe that this should be said
空の下で伝えたい｡
under the sky.
Yeah.
(溝口)≪ああ｡だから
いらないってば｡➡
I don't need anything.
ケーキ買う金くらいあるよ≫
I can afford to buy a cake.
(溝口)わざわざ作らなくていいし
送らなくていいから｡
You don't have to bake or send one.
切るよ｡
だから そろそろＪＡＸＡから➡
I'm hanging up.
Like I said, JAXA's going to call me soon.
かかってくるんだよ｡…ああ｡➡
Yeah.
結果がわかったら すぐまた
連絡するって｡…うん じゃあ｡
I'll call you once I know the results.
Yeah, bye.
まったく…
どこまで過保護なんだよ｡
Seriously...
They can't let go.
Hello, this is Mizoguchi.
はい｡溝口です｡➡
…はい｡
Yes.
はい…はい｡
だああっ‼
(南波母)あ？なに？
Oh, what?
最悪っ！あ いや ナイスだ！
This sucks...
Wait, this is good.
That really hurts...
ぐお～ 痛ってぇ…けど よし！
But I'm glad.
ちょ…ちょっと血も出てるけど➡
I'm even bleeding...
ってへぇ～…とりあえずＯＫ！
But that's okay!
ねえ ムッちゃん
あんたって バカなの？
Um, Mu?
Did you go nuts?
(南波父)なんだ？どした？
Huh? What's wrong?
六太が変なのよぉ お父さん
どうしよう｡私 心配で痩せるわ～｡
Mutta's acting weird, dear. What do we do?
I'll lose weight from the stress.
よそ見してて角に頭ぶつけて➡
He wasn't paying attention, bumped his head, and started bleeding.
血ぃ出てんのに なぜか
喜んじゃってんのよ この子｡
But for some reason, he's happy.
What?
なにぃ!?とうとう頭でも打って
おかしくなったか｡
Did he lose his mind after hitting his head?
だからそうなのよ｡
That's what happened...
《え!?たしかに…》
Huh?
It's true...
《たしかにこれじゃあ
おかしな人だ》
It's true, I'm acting like a total weirdo.
《今さら運がどうとか…➡
It's a waste of time to worry about my luck now.
はっきり言って
無意味な時間だった》
《合格なら宇宙で船外活動➡
If I pass, I'll be going on EVAs in space.
不合格なら就職活動》
If I fail, I'll be looking for work on Earth.
《ただ…それだけのこと》
It's really that simple.
☎(星加)溝口君…｡
(溝口)はい｡
Mizoguchi...
Yes.
☎(星加)残念ながら今回は…➡
I'm sorry to say
不合格となりました｡
that you failed.
《え!?ちょっ…ちょっと待て！》
Eh?
H-Hold on.
は…はい｡
《何かの間違いだろ!?》
O-Oh.
There must be some mistake!
(教師)⦅分からないことが
あったら溝口に聞け｡➡
If you have any questions, ask Mizoguchi.
あいつは何でも知ってる｡➡
He knows everything.
お前らも溝口を
もっと見習えよ｡なっ⦆
(生徒)⦅へ～い⦆
You guys should follow his example, okay?
Sure.
Class Representative
Mizoguchi 16
Kaneyama 5
Mizugami 2
Kawagami 1
Class Representative
Mizoguchi 16
Kaneyama 5
Mizugami 2
Kawagami 1
(溝口)《小･中･高 そして大学｡➡
Grade school, middle school, high school, and college.
常にトップに立ってきた｡
今までずっと》
I was always at the very top.
1st Mizoguchi Yamato
I was always at the top.
⦅溝口君 スゴーイ⦆
⦅さすが生徒会長だな⦆
Mizoguchi's amazing.
That's our student council president.
しちじつごうけん
⦅会長として私は｢質実剛健｣
ほうおんかんしゃ
｢報恩感謝｣という➡
As student council president,
I intend to continue the traditions of hard work and gratitude we have inherited.
先輩が守られてきた伝統ある
校訓を胸に 新しい事への➡
At the same time,
挑戦を忘れない
フロンティア精神にあふれた➡
I promise to lead the student council in trying new ideas.
生徒会の実現を約束します⦆
《僕の指示でみんなが動いた｡➡
Everyone followed my instructions.
誰も意見なんて言わなかった》
No one ever opposed me.
《僕にすべて任せてたんだろ？
だから僕は考えたんだ｡➡
They always let me lead.
So I did all the thinking.
みんなのかわりに考えた｡
何か問題が起こるたび➡
I did the thinking for everyone else.
Because I was the only one who could guide everyone down the correct path.
正しい方向へ導けるのは
僕しかいないんだから》
《リーダーにふさわしいと
誰もが認めてくれていた》
Everyone said that I was a great leader.
僕の…何がいけなかったのか…➡
Would it be possible
教えては もらえませんか？
for you to tell me what it was I did wrong?
溝口君 これはあくまで
僕の意見だけど…｡
Mizoguchi,
this is my personal opinion.
☎(星加)君はリーダーとして
これからどんな職場でも➡
You will make an excellent leader in any job you take.
トップに立てる人材だと思う｡
だがひとつ 足りないことがある｡
But there's one thing you lack.
足りないこと？
One thing I lack?
｢仲間に頼る｣ということだ｡
The ability to depend on others.
To depend on others...
(溝口)《仲間に…頼る》
はい…はい…
ありがとうございました｡
Yes.
Thank you very much.
《今まで誰も 僕に意見なんて
言わなかったのに》
Even now, no one ever speaks their minds around me.
(溝口)⦅点数制でいこうよ｡➡
Let's use a point system.
That would be easiest.
それが一番分かりやすいだろ？➡
これから出される課題全部に
個人の点数を付けていくんだよ⦆
Each person would receive individual scores for each task.
I'm not sure we want to use points at this stage of the process.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)⦅僕は…ここまできたら➡
点数じゃないような
気もするんだけど⦆
《初めて僕に反対意見を言う
まかべ
奴が現れた…真壁ケンジ》
He was the first person who ever disagreed with me...
Makabe Kenji.
⦅僕はそうは思わないな⦆
I don't agree.
So let's work together to find a solution.
⦅ここは
みんなの力を合わせよう⦆
Really?
《何なんだよ
こんな奴がいたのかよ》
So there are people like him out there?
(溝口)《真壁は合格だろう｡
そうでなきゃ…困る》
Makabe must have passed.
That's the only way I can accept this.
あ 原田君か｡私だ｡
Oh, Harada?
It's me.
うん 申し訳ないけど
１つ頼みがあるんだが…｡
Yes.
Sorry, but I need a favor.
《予定の時刻を
２時間以上も過ぎてる》
It's been two hours since they were supposed to start calling.
Could they have forgotten about me?
《忘れられてる？
もしかして…》
Houston, this is Damian.
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)ヒューストン
こちらダミアン｡➡
Hibito was the first offender,
第１号のヒビトに続いて ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨと
ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨも頭をぶつけたよ 天井で｡
and Buddy and Freddy have also hit their heads on the ceiling.
ふふっ…｡だから言ったんだよ｡
基地の天井低いって｡
I told you...
The ceiling in the base is too low.
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)う～ん うかつだった｡
I was too careless.
I just took a little hop...
ちょっと跳ねただけなのにな｡
ヒューストン 次に基地を作る時は
月の低重力と➡
Houston, next time you build a base,
you should raise the ceiling three meters to account for the moon's gravity and our vertical movement.
俺達のジャンプ力を
計算に入れて➡
天井を３メートルぐらいにする
必要がありそうだぞ｡
This is Houston.
かんせいかん
こちらヒューストン｡ハハハハハ！
もしくは
やわらか～い素材で頼む｡
Or use something soft for the ceiling.
発表しないでくれよ｡
月面の男達は➡
Don't let the press find out that the men on the moon are all sporting band-aids.
みんなバンソーコーを
貼ってるなんて…｡
I'm still clean.
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)俺は貼ってないよ｡
別に 発表したって
いんじゃね～の？
Does it really matter?
We can just tell them that you have to wear a band-aid to be an astronaut on the moon.
逆にこう言ってやりゃいいよ｡
バンソーコーを貼ってこそ
月面の宇宙飛行士！
《ちょっと～ ＪＡＸＡ》
Come on, JAXA...
《まだかよ!?》
Honestly!
西からワッショイ
The wind...
The wind goes hey-ho...
Hey-ho from the west...
Hey-ho like the wind.
今度は～
Then a hey-ho from the north...
What is this weird song?
《なんだよ その変な歌…》
Hey-ho, hey-ho, hey-ho!
アッホラ ワッショイ
Hey-ho, hey-ho, hey-ho, hey-ho!
ワッショイ！
ワッショイ‼
Hey-ho!
ワッショイ？
Hey-ho?
Er, sorry!
いやっ じゃなくて もしもし
はい 南波です スミマセン｡
Hello, this is Nanba...
Sorry about that.
はい…はい…え!?
Yes... Yes.
Huh?
Hey-ho, hey-ho, hey-ho.
は はい｡りょ 了解しました｡
(父)《ワッショイ…》
Y-Yes...
I-I understand.
What's wrong?
ど～したの？
わかんない…｡
I don't get it.
どこ行くの？
公園！よくわかんね～けど➡
Where are you going?
The park.
Someone from JAXA asked me to meet him there since he's in the area.
近くまで来たから 出てこれないか
って…ＪＡＸＡの人が｡
あ そうなの｡
Oh, okay...
行ってくる｡
I'm off, then.
あ‼ついでに大根…ん？
Oh, buy some daikon while...
Oh, what?
あらっ 何？散歩に行きたい？
Do you want to go for a walk?
あらそう 公園に…｡
Ah, of course...
You want to go to the park.
Is this how the announcement is supposed to happen?
《こういうもんなのか!?
合格発表って｡➡
ＪＡＸＡの人が
わざわざ来るのか？》
JAXA actually sends people to meet us?
ありがとっ‼
Thank you.
なに くつってんの？
おしそみる｡
What are you making?
Miso soup.
(星加)よう！
Hey.
Huh?
《あれ この人は確か…》
Isn't he...
面接官の中にいた方ですよね？
You were one of the interviewers, right?
ああ よく覚えてたな｡
だが それ以前に➡
Yes, I'm glad you remember.
But have you forgotten our numerous prior meetings?
何度も会ってたことは
思い出せないのか？
Huh?
え？以前に？
Prior?
What happened to your forehead, Afro?
どうしたモジャ君 そのおでこ｡
⦅ん？どうしたモジャ君
そのおでこ⦆
Hmm?
What happened to your forehead, Afro?
⦅あ～ ケガした⦆
Oh, I got hurt.
あ あなた…え？
あのフサフサの!?
W-Wait, you're...
Th-The guy with all that hair?
そうだ 昔は｢ＪＡＸＡのライオン｣
と呼ばれていた程➡
Yep.
I used to have so much hair, they called me the Lion of JAXA.
フッサフサだったけどな｡➡
まあ しょうがねぇよ｡
酸性雨のせいだ｡
Well, it happens.
Blame the acid rain.
⦅宇宙飛行士に
なれる人っていうのは➡
It takes more than ability to become an astronaut.
ししつ
その資質だけじゃなくて 実は強い
運を持ち合わせてるんです｡➡
You must also have luck on your side.
残念ながら 私には
その運がありませんでした⦆
I'm sorry to say that I wasn't one of the lucky ones.
アンアン ク～ン｡
シー！シー！
Shh... Shh!
モジャ君…いや 南波六太君｡
Afro...
No,
Nanba Mutta.
Yes.
はい｡
我々ＪＡＸＡは 君を…｡
We at JAXA
would...
(星加)⦅台本覚えてんのか
あいつら？➡
They've memorized the script?
Those kids are the ones who end up becoming astronauts...
あ～いうのが将来 宇宙飛行士に
なったりすんだよな⦆
君を…宇宙飛行士として
迎えます｡
...would like to welcome you as a new astronaut.
おめでとう！君には運がある！
Congratulations.
You're one of the lucky ones.
Th-Thank you very much.
あ ありがとうございます｡
Sorry about being so late.
遅くなって悪かったね｡
直接 伝えたかったんだ｡
I wanted to tell you in person.
Don't be sorry...
いえ…ありがとうございます｡
Thank you very much.
(チリン チリン チリン…)
(母)う…うう…｡
やったわ あの子｡
うう…よかったわ｡➡
He did it...
I'm so happy for him.
アポちゃん
ケーキ買って帰りましょ｡
Apo,
let's buy a cake and go home.
(アポ)ワン！
じゃあ 行こうか 六太君｡
え!?行くってどこに？
Then let's go, Mutta.
Huh?
Wh-Where are we going?
向こうに車を待たせてある｡
There's a car waiting for us.
We should head straight to the press conference.
これから さっそく記者会見だ！
他の合格者も
みんな向かってる頃だ｡
The other new astronauts are waiting.
みんなも…｡
The other new astronauts?
(星加)さあ 急ごう‼
Let's hurry!
(チリン チリン チリン…)
ありがとね｡
Thank you.
さぁ この中が会見場だ｡
Well, we're holding the press conference inside.
いやいや コートを｡
え？あっ はい｡
No, your coat...
Eh? R-Right...
Th-Thank you.
お お願いします｡
おう｡
Sure.
さあ 扉を開いて中へ｡
Now, open the door and step inside.
今日から君の
宇宙飛行士人生が始まるぞ！
This is the first day of your life as an astronaut.
My right hand spent its days afraid of losing something
but wished to be held by my left hand
I lead you by the hand
Is my hand only there to hold my own hand now?
I can't lose it
Amidst my nagging disappointment that I can do nothing
I felt I wanted to do something
I let go again
I'm not alone in this world
If my hands can only hold two things
then I hope one of them is you
Not alone, not alone
I want our hearts to be connected
I want to be connected
＜モジャ君
これから さっそく記者会見だ｡➡
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#38 Eleventh E-mail
Afro, the press conference is about to start.
今日から君の
宇宙飛行士人生が始まるぞ！＞
This is the first day of your life as an astronaut.
I'm an astronaut now...
＜今日から宇宙飛行士だなんて
やっぱ まだ実感ねえな＞
I still can't believe it.
＜そんな中 やっさんからの
メールが１０件も届く＞
Meanwhile, Ya has sent me ten e-mails.
＜ほとんどは 私の記者会見に
対するツｯコミだったものの…＞
Mostly criticism of my press conference performance.
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Eleventh E-mail"
＜日々人…
お前は いつ実感した？➡
Hibito, when did it finally sink in
自分が宇宙飛行士に
選ばれたってことを＞
that you were an astronaut?
パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
Double check, triple check!
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真で～す！
カッコイイ！
Cool stuff!